Guide to the Michael Robinson Papers MSS.494
Fales Library and Special Collections
Michael Robinson Papers
1969-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Robinson, Michael, 1956-
MSS.494
55.54 Gigabytes in 347 audio files and 1 archived website.
1 websites in 1 archived website.
55.54 Gigabytes in 347 audio files.
Michael Robinson is an American composer, performer, and musicologist whose works combine American, South Asian, and European traditions to create instrumental pieces. This collection contains an archived copy of his website, which features a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, examples of his works in the form of embedded video and audio files and prose writings, and images of Robinson. The collection also consists of 347 audio files representing the body of Robinson’s musical work, including original and remastered recordings from 104 of his albums. Materials in the collection were created between 1969-2017.
Box Electronic records
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Custodial History
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Audio files were aquired by the University via an August 2017 network transfer from the creator.
Arrangement
The collection was arranged in alphabetical order by title of project or publication, or format of material.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michael Robinson, September 2016. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2017.048 and 2017.150.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Scope and Contents
The Michael Robinson Papers contain an archived copy of his website, which features a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, interviews of and by the artist, examples of his works in the form of embedded video files and prose writings, and images of Robinson, who is a composer, performer, and musicologist. The collection also consists of 347 audio files representing the body of Robinson’s musical work, including original and remastered recordings from 104 of his albums. Materials in the collection were created between 1969-2017.
Robinson’s music, featured both on his website and the hard drive of audio files, is influenced by American, South Asian, and European musical traditions. It combines traditional instruments from many cultures with new performance techniques and electronic components. His website also includes his writings on the subjects of music, art, and basketball. The bulk of the images of Robinson featured on his site depict him at his home in Los Angeles.
Biographical Note
Michael Robinson is a prolific American composer who uses various instruments to create and perform his South Asian and European inspired music. Active since 1969, he has composed over 450 pieces on 113 albums. He has been a lecturer at such institutions as UCLA, Bard College, and California State University, and has produced a series of interviews with masters of various music styles. He currently lives in Los Angeles, California.
Conditions Governing Access
Sound recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
Instrumental Music.; Music |z Southeast Asia; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.; Web sites.; Digital images.
- The Abode of Joy (Remastered), December 11, 2011; 667.3 Megabytes in 9 audio files (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Sound recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
  Scope and Contents
  Album was remastered by Robinson in 2016.
  Songs were recorded between 1972-1984.
- The Abode of Snow (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 601.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_2)
- Adorned with Pearl (Remastered), July 11, 1996; 536.1 Megabytes in 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_3)
  Songs were recorded between 1995-1996.
- African Pillows, September 15, 2010; 538.2 Megabytes in 9 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_4)
  Songs were recorded between 1991-1994.
- Archived Website, May 2017- ongoing; 3 websites in 1 archived website.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://azuremilesrecords.com and issuu.com/azuremiles/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
  Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
  Custodial History
  Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Robinson, Michael, 1956-
- Astral Palace (Remastered), June 11, 1999; 611 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_5)
  The album was remastered by Robinson in 2016.
- August, September 15, 2010; 600.9 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_6)
  Songs were recorded in 1991.
- Bairagi (Remastered), November 11, 2000; 571.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_7)
- Bhairava (Remastered), February 11, 2010; 516.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_8)
- Bhairavi (Remastered), February 11, 2010; 448 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_9)
  Song was recorded in 2009.
- Bhimpalasi (Remastered), September 27, 2001; 1.75 Gigabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_10)
  Album was remeastered by Robinson in 2016.
- Bouquet, September 15, 2010; 481.1 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_11)
  Songs were recorded in 1990.
- Buki, November 11, 2010; 671.7 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_12)
  Song was recorded in 1988.
- California Spring (Remastered), February 11, 2000; 573.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_13)
- Carnelian Compass (Remastered), September 27, 2011; 276.7 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_14)
- Celestial Crocodile and Honu Morning, August 4, 2016; 674.2 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_15)
- Celestial Crocodile and Honu Morning (Remastered), August 4, 2016; 673.7 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_16)
- Chakravaka (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 133.1 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_17)
- Charukeshi (Remastered), June 11, 2002; 608.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_18)
- Chinese Legend (Remastered), October 11, 1997; 524.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_19)
- Crayons, September 15, 2010; 512.5 Megabytes in 11 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_20)
  Songs were recorded from 1990-1991.
- Darbari Kanada (Remastered), December 11, 2006; 616.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_21)
- Dark Yellow (Remastered), May 11, 2000; 510.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_22)
- Dhani (Remastered), September 27, 2003; 1.98 Gigabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_23)
- Dharmavati (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 385.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_24)
- Dhirasankarabharanam (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 388.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_25)
- Earth's Pebbles, September 15, 2010; 517.8 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_26)
  Songs were recorded from 1989-1991.
- Emerald Anklets (Remastered), December 11, 2011; 428.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_27)
- The Fiddler of Dooney (Remastered), November 11, 2012; 304.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_28)
- Fire Monkey (Remastered), January 11, 1994; 710.1 Megabytes in 8 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_29)
- The Forest (Remastered), December 11, 1999; 562.1 Megabytes in 8 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_30)
- Gamanapriya (Remastered), February 11, 2010; 453.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_31)
- Gangadhara (Remastered), August 11, 2002; 532.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_32)
- The Girl in the Photograph (Remastered), September 11, 2010; 408.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_33)
- Hamoa (Remastered), June 11, 1995; 695.9 Megabytes in 9 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_34)
- Hansadhvani (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 386.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_35)
- Hawaiian Rain, September 15, 2010; 581.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_36)
  Songs were recorded between 1989-1990.
- Hummingbird Canyon, June 30, 2014; 470.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_37)
- Hummingbird Canyon (Remastered), June 30, 2014; 432.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_38)
- Indian Jasmine (Remastered), December 11, 1997; 628.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_39)
- Indian Ocean (Remastered), June 11, 1999; 610.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_40)
- Irish Ghost, September 15, 2010; 605 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_41)
- Jaunpuri (Remastered), September 11, 1999; 614.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_42)
- The Jewel Treasure of the Ocean (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 462.8 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_43)
- Kamavardhani (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 410.5 Megabytes in 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_44)
- Kanakangi (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 375.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_45)
- Kaunsi Kanada (Remastered), June 11, 2000; 577.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_46)
- Kirvani (Remastered), November 11, 2000; 540.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_47)
- Kokilapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 379 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_48)
- Lahaina Lanterns (Remastered), March 11, 2013; 443.9 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_49)
- Latangi (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 423.9 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_50)
- Like Rain, September 15, 2010; 534.1 Megabytes in 9 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_51)
- Lilac Dawn, June 19, 2017; 446.6 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_52)
- Lilac Dawn (Remastered), June 19, 2017; 446 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_53)
- The Lotus Girl (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 636.8 Megabytes in 9 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_54)
- Luminous Realms (Remastered), July 11, 1999; 609.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_55)
- Lunar Mansions (Remastered), March 11, 1998; 589.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_56)
- Madhmad Sarang (Remastered), February 11, 2001; 571 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_57)
- Mian ki Malhar (Remastered), January 11, 2003; 555.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_58)
- Monsoon Clouds (Remastered), February 11, 1999; 610.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_59)
- Moonrise and Rain-Mist, December 17, 2015; 556.6 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_60)
- Moonrise and Rain-Mist (Remastered), December 17, 2015; 556.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_61)
- Movement of Time, September 15, 2010; 569.1 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_62)
- Nat Narayan (Remastered), July 11, 2006; 509.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_63)
- Natabhairavi (Remastered), October 21, 2015; 585.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_64)
- Night of Fire (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 553.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_65)
- Nightmarches (Remastered), March 11, 2012; 316.3 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_66)
- North Africa (Remastered), December 11, 1999; 516.3 Megabytes in 6 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_67)
- Onyx Sands (Remastered), October 11, 2010; 400.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_68)
- Patdeep, Jait, Magh (Remastered), May 11, 2000; 659.2 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_69)
- Peridot Pond (Remastered), February 11, 2011; 404.7 Megabytes in 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_70)
- Photosynthesis (Remastered), December 11, 1999; 535.5 Megabytes in 6 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_71)
- Pink Monkey (Remastered), September 11, 2010; 413.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_72)
- Polynesian Woman (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 659.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_73)
- Portrait, September 15, 2010; 488.5 Megabytes in 9 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_74)
  Songs were recorded between 1989-1991.
- Puriya Dhanashri (Remastered), February 11, 2002; 695.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_75)
- Purple and Brown (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 678.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_76)
- Rageshri (Remastered), March 11, 2001; 566 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_77)
- Rajasthani Spring, June 11, 2015; 325.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_78)
- Rajasthani Spring (Remastered), June 11, 2015; 325 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_79)
- Ramapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 428.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_80)
- Robinson Gardens (Remastered), December 11, 1999; 572.7 Megabytes in 5 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_81)
- Ruby Cars, June 23, 2017; 607.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_82)
- Ruby Soul (Remastered), July 11, 2012; 204.8 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_83)
- Rusabhapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 385.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_84)
- Sagarmatha (Remastered), June 11, 1998; 611.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_85)
- Shankara (Remastered), September 11, 2006; 508.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_86)
- Snow and Wood (Remastered), December 11, 2000; 689.9 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_87)
- Snow Leopard Meadow (Remastered), March 11, 1999; 610.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_88)
- Summer Morning (Remastered), September 11, 2010; 404.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_89)
- Teahouse, September 15, 2010; 504.7 Megabytes in 8 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_90)
- Tendrils (Remastered), December 11, 1995; 709.5 Megabytes in 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_91)
- The Spirit Pool, November 11, 2014; 424.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_92)
- Todi (Remastered), December 11, 2006; 586.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_93)
- Topaz (Remastered), May 10, 2017; 346.5 Megabytes in 5 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_94)
- Touch a Color (Remastered), September 15, 2010; 659 Megabytes in 7 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_95)
- Trembling Flowers (Remastered), July 11, 1991; 756.8 Megabytes in 11 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_97)
- Vachaspati (Remastered), May 11, 2005; 607.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_98)
- Wine Breath, September 15, 2010; 558.9 Megabytes in 10 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_99)
  Recordings for this album were made between 1991-1992.
- Wings of the Owls, September 15, 2010; 613.1 Megabytes in 2 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_100)
- Yaman (Remastered), June 11, 2006; 609.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_101)
- Yellow and Black, September 15, 2010; 611.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_102)
- Yellow Silk, November 11, 2010; 634.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_494_ER_103)